<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20250920</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC11831363</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1093/gbe/evaf018</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC11831363</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">39960155</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">evaf018</infon><infon key="elocation-id">evaf018</infon><infon key="issue">2</infon><infon key="license">This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/), which permits unrestricted reuse, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2025</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Correction to: The Evolution of Temperature and Desiccation-Related Protein Families in Tardigrada Reveals a Complex Acquisition of Extremotolerance</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>149</offset><text>This is a correction to: James F Fleming, Davide Pisani, Kazuharu Arakawa, The Evolution of Temperature and Desiccation-Related Protein Families in Tardigrada Reveals a Complex Acquisition of Extremotolerance, Genome Biology and Evolution, Volume 16, Issue 1, January 2024, https://doi.org/10.1093/gbe/evad217</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>459</offset><text>In the originally published online version of this manuscript, details in the caption to Figure 7 were errored.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>572</offset><text>These should read: “[…]CAHS is represented in red, MAHS in purple, SAHS in green, EtAHS alpha in yellow, EtAHS beta in pink, and MRE11 in blue.[…]” instead of: “[…] CAHS is represented in blue, MAHS in purple, SAHS in green, EtAHS alpha in red, EtAHS beta in orange, and MRE11 in black.[…]”.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>880</offset><text>These errors are outlined only in this correction notice to preserve the version of record.</text></passage></document>
</collection>